ANKUR SINGH

+1 (408) 941 - 5818 | mleankursingh@gmail.com | ankur-singh.github.io

Summary _

With 4+ years in Product Management, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, and Software Development, I'm passionate about solving business problems, building ML products, and contributing to open source. Currently pursuing a Masters in Software Engineering at SJSU. In my previous role, at Zoop.One, built and led a high-performing team, deploying 4 ML services in 10 months, yielding impressive results.

Skills_

Languages & Databases
Python, Postgres, SQLite3, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, ElasticSearch

API Development & Web apps
Flask, FastAPI, Rest API, gRPC, Web Socket, Postman, Streamlit, Gradio
Git, GitHub Actions, PySpark, Python Packaging, Design Patterns, Unit Testing
Pandas, Sklearn, XGBoost, Keras, Pytorch, HF Transformers, LangChain
DevOps & MLOps
Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Kubeflow, Terraform, TorchServe

Work Experience_

Al Solution Intern, @ Intel

Remote (May. 2023 - Present)

- Intel Cloud Optimization Modules (ICOM) for AWS: Finetune GPT-2 Small model on OpenWebText dataset.
- Training with PyTorch's Distributed Data Parallel (DDP) on CPUs using IPEX and oneCCL.
- Technologies: Pytorch, HF Transformers, Datasets, Accelerate, Kubernetes, Kubeflow, AWS

Graduate Research Assistant, @ SJSU

San Jose, CA (Sept. 2022 - May 2023)

- Worked on improving Knowledge Distillation performance for Traffic Flow Prediction.
- Deployed various detection and segmentation models on Edge devices for real-time inference.
- Technologies: Pytorch, Docker, Jetson, ROS2 Humble, TorchServe, ONNX, NVIDIA Triton, TFLite

ML Team Lead, @ Zoop.one

Pune, India (Sept. 2021 - July 2022)

As a Founding Member of the ML team, built a strong team and scaled ML usage company wide. Enhanced MLOps with annotation tools, model registry, monitoring, training, and other best practices implementation.

- Developed **OCR service** for Identity Cards with 7+ deep learning models, achieving 6x faster speed, higher accuracy, and multi-line field support.
- Created a Heatmap Regression-based **document extractor service** for auto-cropping documents/ID cards, with a lightweight TFLite model for edge deployment (4.4 MB).
- Led development of a real-time **liveliness service** with features like face detection, recognition, matching, achieving low latency (~150 ms) for real-time video feed inference.

Technologies: Pytorch, MLFlow, OpenCV, Label Studio, Docker, FastAPI, ONNX, Wandb, FiftyOne, TorchServe

CoFounder and CEO, @ Ai Adventures LLP

Pune, India (Aug. 2018 - Sept. 2021)

- Built the tech-stack required for generation, deployment & distribution of all courses.
- Lead development of various client projects like Image Search, Smart Attendance, Parking management.

Education -

• Masters in Software Engineering (spl. Data Science) @ SJSU

CGPA: **3.9**/4.0 (Aug. 2022 - May 2024)

BTech in Information Technology @ COEP

CGPA: 7.67/10 (Aug. 2014 - May 2018)

Competitions -

• Targeted Pest Control @ Intel Innovation, 2022

Grand Prize

• Shopee - Price Match Guarantee @ Kaggle

Bronze Medal (207th / 2426)

• Global Wheat Detection @ Kaggle

Bronze Medal (191st / 2245)

Mechanisms of Action @ Kaggle

Bronze Medal (318th / 4373)

OSS: Author of colab-everything (32K+ downloads) and torchserve-client python packages published on PyPI.